Guide to the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection Photo.002
New York University Archives
- Series I: Oversized Photographs and Drawings
  - NYU Track Team group photograph, circa 1903; 19.5x15 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 14x11 Mounting size: 19.5x15 Recto: hole in photograph, breaks and flaking of mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark discolorations, brown lines, writing in pencil, hole through photo and mounting Condition: Fair (Box 28)
  - NYU Track Team group with dog mascot: photograph and negative, circa 1904-1905; 20x16 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13.5x10 Mounting size: 20x16 Recto: writing in black pen on mounting, scratches and marks on mountings, pieces missing from mounting along the edge, Verso: writing in pencil, writing in black pen, heavy discoloration, stains from water(?) Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - Gymnastics Team 1907 (and Inter-Collegiate Champions 1907), 1906; 20.5x16 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10 Mounting size: 20.5x16 Recto: extreme discoloration/yellowing, mounting and photo are broken into two pieces, water stain, flaking along edges Verso: writing in pencil, dark stains Condition: Poor (Box 24)
  - Negative of Photograph for NYU Gymnastics Team 1906-1907, 8x10 negative of black and white photograph. Stored in glassine paper. Condition: Good (Box 24)
  - NYU Basketball Team (photograph and negative), 1909-1910; 20x16 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 13.5x11 Mounting size: 20x16 General: multiple breaks, cracks, and pieces missing Recto: large break down left side, writing in white from negative, writing in black pen, discoloration/yellowing Verso: heavy surface dirt, skinning, breaks and cracks in mounting Condition: Poor (Box 24)
  - NYU Basketball Team 1919-1920 National Champions, 2 copies of this item exist: Copy 1: 13.5x10.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and Photo same size Recto: scratches and breaks, bottom left corner missing, writing in black from negative Verso: label adhered to mounting, discoloration from adhesive, heavy discoloration, breaks in mounting Condition: Fair Copy 2: Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 17.5x15 Recto: some surface dirt on mounting, bend at top left corner, writing in black writing from negative Verso: pressure adhesive, skinning of mounting Condition: Good (Box 24)
  - NYU Basketball Team 1919-1920 National Champions, 2 copies of this item exist: Copy 1: 13.5x10.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and Photo same size Recto: scratches and breaks, bottom left corner missing, writing in black from negative Verso: label adhered to mounting, discoloration from adhesive, heavy discoloration, breaks in mounting Condition: Fair Copy 2: Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 17.5x15 Recto: some surface dirt on mounting, bend at top left corner, writing in black writing from negative Verso: pressure adhesive, skinning of mounting Condition: Good (Box 24)
  - NYU Football Team(?), n.d.; 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: water stains and or deposits on photo and mounting, pieces missing from mounting, surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration of mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks, scratches Condition: Fair (Flat-file 8, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Football Team, undated; 13x9.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Mounting and photo same size Recto: heavy discoloration and surface dirt, bottom right corner missing Verso: writing in pencil, heavy discoloration and surface dirt, stains from water (?), scratches Condition: Fair (Flat-file 8, Drawer 9)
  - Lacrosse Team group photograph, 1928 (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Lacrosse Team, action photograph, circa 1890 (Box Shared University Archives 131)
  - Jose de Capriles and Hugo Castello of NYU Fencing Team, 8x10 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: planar distortion/curling Recto: small tear on top edge Verso: yellowing/discoloration (from mounting?), stamp in black ink, pressure adhesive. Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and fencer of NYU Fencing Team, 8x10 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: paper and adhesive desposits (possible from the removal of mounting?) Verso: pressure adhesive, heavy surface dirt, brown spotting Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and NYU Fencing Team- left to right: N. Lerner, J. Archer, V. Butockares, H. Castello, J. Cagnina, D Shriner, 9.5x8 black and white photograph (silver gelatin?) Recto: mirroring, discoloration/silvering, heavy surface dirt Verso: yellowing/discoloration, small black marks Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 10)
  - Hugo Castello and NYU Fencing Team Members (?), 14x11 black and white photograph General: planar distortion Verso: black stamp, black marks, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Flat-file 8, Drawer 10)
  - Fencing Team- Individual Intercollegiate Medalists for 1932-1933 season, 12x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 10x8 Mounting size: 12z11 Recto: writing in black pen on mounting, bottom right corner of mounting missing, yellowing and surface dirt on mounting Verso: photo attached to mounting with pressure adhesive, yellowing/discoloration, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - Fencing Champion- Hugo Castello 1935 Intercollegiate Three-Weapon Champion with Coach Julio M. Castello and Captain Henry P. Stral, 14x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 10x8.5 Mounting size: 14x11 Recto: heavy surface dirt on mounting, Verso:skinning of mounting, sever discoloration, heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Sabre Fencing Team 1935- Max Frank, Jordan Uttal, and Captain Henry P. Stral, 11x14 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 8x10 Mounting size: 11x14 Recto: tear in mounting, black marks on mounting Verso: severe discoloration, writing in blue pencil Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Fencing Team- 1936 Intercollegiate Three-Weapon Champions, 14x13 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 10x8 Mounting size: 14x13 Recto: corners chipped from mounting, some yellowing of mounting Verso: severe yellowing/discoloration, 2 writings in pencil, photo attached to mounting with pressure adhesive, black pencil marks on mounting Condition: good (Box 28)
  - Dinner for Professor John J. Stevenson of New York University, February 22, 1909; 18x12 mounted black and white photograph 3 copies of this item exist- 2 in good condition, 1 in fair General: planar distortion, tear in photo and mounting Recto: writing in white from negative, tear along right side, bottom right corner missing, breaks along edges Verso: writing in pen, scratches, flaking along edges, heavy surface dirt Condition: 2 Good and 1 Fair (Box 28)
  - Annual Dinner for NYU Engineering Alumni, February 11, 1911; 20.5x11.5 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 19.5x11 Mounting size: 20.5x11.5 Recto: scratches and surface dirt on photograph, flaking along edges of mounting, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, stamp in black ink Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - Dinner for Dean Hering of New York University- Hotel Manhattan, May 29, 1916; 18x14 mounted black and white photograph 2 copies of this mounted image exist Photo size:13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 18x14 Recto: heavy surface dirt, writing in black pen, stamp in black ink, white writing from negative, bottom left corner of mounting bent Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, dark marks (possibly fingerprints) Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Faculty Dinner in honor of Dean E.J. Kilduff group photograph, June 3, 1936; 2 copies exist 20x12 black and white photograph on fiber paper General: curling/planar distortion Recto: some tearing/small pieces missing from edges Verso: two writings in pencil, severe discoloration, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Faculty Club- 25 Year Dinner, with name key, April 29, 1937; 14x11 black and white photograph on fiber Recto: small tears and bends along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt, two stamps in purple ink, pressure adhesive repairing tear in top right corner Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - Meehan Men of NYU Reunion Dinner, November 26, 1948; 18x9 black and white photograph on fiber paper Recto: bends along left edge, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, brown stains Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Class of 1911 Reunion, September 30, 1949; 18.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: large tears, breaks and bends, two writings in white ink from negative Verso: surface dirt, mark in purple pencil Condition: poor (Box 28)
  - Testimonial Dinner for NYU Faculty Members with 25 Years of Service, March 22, 1952; 18.5x10 black and white photograph General: key and labeling included with photograph Recto: some yellowing along border, small bends along edges Verso: heavy surface dirt and some yellow stains Condition: Good (Box 28)
  - NYU Varsity Baseball Team, 1899; 16x13 mounted black and white photograph (silver gelatin print?) Photo size: 13x10 Mounting size: 16x13 Recto: scratches on photograph, deposits from adhesive and mounting, writing in silver pen, writing in pencil, bottom corners missing from mounting Verso: writing in pencil, writing in pen, heavy surface dirt, corners missing from mounting Condition: Fair (Box 28)
  - NYU Baseball Team group photograph, 1920; 17x14 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 15.5x12.5 Mounting size: 17x14 Recto: writing in black pen, writing in white from negative, mounting broken and missing pieces from edges and corners, heavy surface dirt, black marks on mounting and photograph, scratches on photograph Verso: black marks (possible fingerprints), heavy surface dirt, flaking of mounting, black lines Condition: Fair (although mounting should probably be removed) (Box 28)
  - NYU Baseball Team, 1924-1925; 16x13 mounted black and white photograph on fiber paper Photo size: 12x9 Mounting size: 16x13 Recto: writing in black pen, mounting broken and missing pieces from edges and corners, heavy surface dirt, black marks on mounting and photograph, scratches on photograph Verso: black marks (possible fingerprints), heavy surface dirt, flaking of mounting, black lines Condition: Fair (although mounting should probably be removed) (Box 28)
  - NYU School of Education Alumni Luncheon group table photograph, May 7, 1932; 20x12 black and white photograph General: planar distortion, curling Recto: black marks, curling, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks, stamp in purple ink, red marks, curling Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU School of Education Alumni Association group table, April 4, 1936; 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, Alumni Group dressed in missionary and African native costumes with make-up, 1914; 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph General: planar distortion Photo size: 14x10 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: some surface dirt Verso: two writing in pencils Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, Alumni Group action scene, dressed in missionary and African native costumes with make-up, 1914; 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13x9.5 Mounting size: 15.5x12.5 Recto: dark stains, heavy surface dirt on mounting, embossing on mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, black marks Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Commencement, University Heights, group in white costumes with instruments and flags, carrying "Good Ship Piffle" sign, 1914; 15.5x12.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 12x13.5 Mounting size: 15x5x12.5 Genereal: planar distortion Recto: color distortion/silvering, some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Annual NYU Commerce Alumni Dinner, May 7, 1936; 12x20 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black marks Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - 20th Anniversary Dinner for NYU Commerce Class of 1917, January 16, 1937; 21x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20.5x12 Rectowriting in white from negative, cracking along edges of photograph, surface dirt photo and mounting, crackling along surface of photo Verso: some surface dirt, deposit from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Commerce Gridiron Dinner (2 copies), June 2, 1937; 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist- 1 in good condition, 1 in fair Recto: break in center of photo (possibly from folding), writing in white ink from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, two writings in pencil Condition: 1 Fair, 1 Good (Box 29)
  - 10th Annual Reunion for NYU School of Commerce- Class of 1917, January 29, 1927; 20.5x13 mounted black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 20.5x13 Recto: heavy surface dirt along edges, white writing from negative, planar distortion, discoloration/yellowing Verso: heavy surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, writing in pencil Condition: 1 Good and 1 poor (Box 29)
  - The Golden Anniversary Ceremonial Dinner- NYU School of Commerce, April 11, 1950; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some rippling along the edge Verso: surface dirt, strips of pressure adhesive, fingerprints Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - 40th Reunion of NYU School of Commerce Class of 1916, April 18, 1956; 17.5x10 black and white photograph General: break down the center of the photo (possibly from folding) Recto: writing in white from negative Verso: writing in pencil, some rippling along edges Condition: Fair (Box 29)
  - 40th Reunion of NYU School of Commerce- Class of 1917, January 17, 1957; 2 copies of this item exist- one mounted, one unmounted- both in good condition 22x14 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 22x14 Recto: mark in pencil, some surface dirt, white writing from negative, planar distortion Verso: some surface dirt, discoloration/yellowing, deposits from adhesive, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Student Body 1909 from 1910 Violet Yearbook: photograph, 20x16 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, heavy surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Smoker Class of 1933 NYU Dinner, December 17, 1931; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: scratches, discoloration/yellowing, bottom left corner is missing, some breaks, chemical stains(?) Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in black ink, heavy surface dirt, dark brown stains, pressure adhesives Condition: Fair (Box 29)
  - Session of the Conference of Universities at the Waldorf Astoria, November 17, 1932; 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: stains (from chemicals?), curling and bends, rippling along edges Verso: writing in pencil, black marks, heavy surface dirt, yellow stains (from chemical?) Condition: 1 Fair and 1 Good (Box 29)
  - Dinner given by Dr. Albert Warren Ferris for NYU Class of 1878 Classmates, May 30, 1908; 17x12 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 17x11.5 Mounting size: 17x12 Recto: white writing from negative Verso: some surface dirt, two writings in pencil, stamp in black ink, writing in black pen Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Dinner for Inauguration of E.E. Brown as NYU Chancelor, November 9, 1911; 20x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 19.5x11.5 Mounting size: 20x11.5 Recto: some surface dirt, bottom left corner missing, white writing from negative Verso: two writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Club- Birthday Dinner in Honor of Kate S. Chittenden given by the Alumni Association of the American Institute of Applied Music, April 17, 1936; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt, cracking on surface of photograph, tears along edges, writing in white from negative Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in black ink, pressure adhesive strips, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Alumni Association NYU Department of Arts and Sciences, February 9, 1909; 18x12 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 17.5x11.5 Mounting size: 18x12 Recto: white writing from negative, corners missing from mounting, small tears along edges of photo Verso: writing in pencil, surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - NYU Class of 1907 Dinner, undated; 14x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 13.5x10.5 Mounting size: 14x11 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, writing in white from negative Verso: three writings in pencil, heavy surface dirt, dark stains Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Testimonial Dinner in Honor of Henry Bailey Rathbone of NYU (framed), April 25, 1941; 19.5x10.5 framed black and white photograph Recto: writing in white from negative Verso: not visible through frame Condition: Good (Box 29)
  - Basketball Dinner for 1933-1934 season, at NYU Athletic Club, 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - NYU Football Dinner at the Biltmore, December 11, 1930; 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: surface dirt, planar distortion/curling, white writing in Verso: heavy surface dirt, paper label affixed, writing in pencil, writing in black pen, stamp in red ink, small breaks along edges Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Annual NYU Letter Club Dinner in Honor of 1928 Football Team, March 5, 1929; 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: planar distortion/curling, heavy surface dirt, writing in white from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration, three stamps in purple ink, writings in pencil. Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Kappa Sigma Annual Dinner for New York University, March 26, 1913; 19x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size:18.5x11 Mounting size:19x11.5 Recto: some yellowing/discoloration, writing in white from negative Verso: two writings in pencil, writing in black pen, black fingerprints, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - NYU Class of 1930 University Heights- First Reunion Zeta Psi Club, May 16, 1936; 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: surface dirt, writing in white from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Annual Norris Dinner NYU Nu Epsilon Phi Gamma Delta, May 9, 1922; 16.5x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size:15.5x10 Mounting size: 16.5x11 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, writing in pencil, white writing from negative, bottom left corner missing from mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt key to photograph included Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Anniversary Dinner of NYU Chapter of Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity, June 6, 1968; 14x10 black and white photograph Recto: breaks in photograph, writing in white from negative, curling/planar distortion Verso: pencil mark, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - NYU Omicron Kappa Upsilon- Omega Chapter Annual Dinner, May 22, 1957; 19x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, writing in white from negative, some surface dirt Verso: yellow marks, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - First Annual Dinner- NYU Beta Gamma Sigma, December 2, 1933; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: planar distortion/curling, tearing along edges, some pieces missing from edges, white writing from negative Verso: writing in red pencil, heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity- NYU Chapter, December 5, 1967; 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: red mark Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner: in small room, men sitting at two long tables, some standing in back, undated; 15x10.5 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner: in ballroom with NYU banners hanging (table numbers 18, 19, 20 in foreground), undated; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: curling, planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner: in small room with American and British flags and NYU banner hanging on wall, men dressed in black tie, undated; 20x13 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 20x13 Recto: cracking on surface of photograph, heavy surface dirt, Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark stains, writing in pencil Condition: Fair (Box 30)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner: in ballroom, with round tables and one head table, men in black time, women in formal wear, undated; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: breaks (from rolling) Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, breaks, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Fair (Box 30)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner: in ballroom, with combination of round and long tables, plus head table on stage, includes hanging banners for College of Arts and Science, Graduate School of Business Administration, and for School of Education, plus New York banner, undated; 22x14 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, white writing from negative, tears along edges, bends at corners Verso: extremely heavy surface dirt, writings in pencil, stamp in black ink, black marks Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - New York University Testimonial Dinner to NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown, May 3, 1933; 22x14 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: heavy surface dirt, writing in white from negative, rippling along edges, bottom right corner missing Verso: cracks and breaks along back surface, rippling along edges, heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - A Little Dinner to "Porky" By a Few Friends at NYU- New York Alumni Club, December 29, 1936; 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: yellowing, heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black marks Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Dinner for NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown- 15th Anniversary (2 copies, 1 negative), November 8, 1926; 23.5x12.5 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: heavy surface dirt, tears along top edge, white writing from negative Verso: yellowing, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Friendship Luncheon Tendered for NYU Dean John William Withers, May 14, 1938; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirst, tears and breaks along edges, pressure adhesive along edge Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, pressure adhesive Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - Tendered to Dr. Frank H. Sommer by the NYU Law Alumni Association for his 25th Anniversary as Dean (5 copies), January 30, 1941; 20x12 black and white photograph 5 copies of this item exist Condition: Good (Box 30)
  - 13th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU, December 19, 1925; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, tattered edges, white writing from negative, bottom right corner missing, break in center of photo Verso: heavy surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil, stamp in blue ink Condition: Fair (Box Shared University Archives 133)
  - 14th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU, December 11, 1926; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, top right corner is bent Verso: surface dirt/fingerprints, two writings in red pencil Condition: Good (Box Shared University Archives 133)